Joel Oppenheimer Papers 1990.0056
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series I: Correspondence, undated, 1947-1988
  - Subseries A: Incoming Correspondence, undated, 1953-1988
    - "Wa" to "We", undated (Box 8:244)
    - "Wel" to "Wi", undated (Box 8:245)
    - "Wil" to "Wy", undated (Box 8:246)
    - Wakoski, Diane, 1971-1974 (Box 9:247)
    - Waldman, Anne, 1967-1986 (Box 9:248)
    - Wang, David Rafael, 1959 (Box 9:249)
    - Wasserman, Seymour (JO's brother-in-law?), 1966-1974 (Box 9:250)
    - Weinberger, Tony, 1972-1988 (Box 9:251)
    - Whalen, Philip (photocopies - originals not present), 1971-1973 (Box 9:252)
    - Whitney, John D., 1975-1977 (Box 9:253)
    - Wilentz, Eli, 1968-1985 (Box 9:254)
    - Williams, Galen, 1968-1981 (Box 9:255)
    - Williams, Jonathan, 1954-1977 (Box 9:256)
    - Williams, Jonathan, 1978-1988 (Box 9:257)
    - Williams, William Carlos (1 pc.), 1956 (Box 9:258)
    - Wrenn, Chip, 1975-1976 (Box 9:259)
    - "X" to "Y" to "Z", undated (Box 9:260)
    - Ziegler, Alan, 1971-1975 (Box 9:261)
    - Zukofsky, Louis (2 pcs.), 1961-1962 (Box 9:262)
  - Subseries B: Outgoing Correspondence, undated
    - "A", undated (Box 9:263)
    - "B", undated (Box 9:264)
    - "C", undated (Box 9:265)
    - "D" to "E", undated (Box 9:266)
    - "F" to "G", undated (Box 9:267)
    - "H" to "I" to "J", undated (Box 9:268)
    - "K", undated (Box 9:269)
    - "L", undated (Box 9:270)
    - "M", undated (Box 9:271)
    - "N" to "O", undated (Box 9:272)
    - "P" to "Q", undated (Box 9:273)
    - "R", undated (Box 9:274)
    - "S", undated (Box 9:275)
    - "T" to "U", undated (Box 9:276)
    - "V" to "W", undated (Box 9:277)
    - "X" to "Y" to "Z", undated (Box 9:278)
    - Outgoing - not identified, 1970-1972 (Box 9:279)
    - Additional printouts of outgoing correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 9:280)
  - Subseries C: Subject Correspondence, undated, 1947-1988
    - Solicitations from fraternities at MIT, 1947 (Box 10:281)
    - College life prior to JO's arrival at Black Mountain, 1948-1950 (Box 10:282)
    - Letters by Ed Dorn, Robert Creeley, and Gary Snyder for "Paterson Society", 1960-1961 (Box 10:283)
    - Telegrams received at JO's second wedding (to Helen), 1966 (Box 10:284)
    - Materials regarding abandoned newspaper project (project involved JO, Leonard Shecter, Pete Hamill), 1967 (Box 10:285)
    - Memos and clippings related to Group 212 Summer Project, 1967 (Box 10:286)
    - Various postcards and wedding announcements, 1967-1970 (Box 10:287)
    - Correspondence and poetry submissions from aspiring poets (sent to St. Mark's Poetry Project?), ca. 1966-1968 (Box 10:288)
    - Correspondence and administrative documents relating to St. Mark's Poetry Project, 1967-1968 (Box 10:289)
    - Correspondence regarding film and drama projects (film version of Great American Desert and other abandoned projects), 1968-1970 (Box 10:290)
    - New York State Council on the Arts, 1967-1970 (Box 10:291)
    - Correspondence regarding readings and professional activity, 1966-1968 (Box 10:292)
    - Correspondence and other material regarding poetry reading by JO in Saratoga, NY, 1968 (Box 10:293)
    - Requests for Submissions, ca. 1967-1969 (Box 10:294)
    - Announcements and Mailings, 1968-1970 (Box 10:295)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Company - regarding publication of In Time and JO's work as poetry consultant, 1968-1969 (Box 10:296)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Company - regarding JO's work as poetry reader, includes correspondence by JO, Eugene Rachlis, Connie Gia, Betty Kelly, and others, 1969-1974 (Box 10:297)
    - City College of CUNY - materials regarding poetry course taught by JO, 1969 (Box 10:298)
    - Correspondence regarding JO review of poetry TSS by Paul Pines (includes photocopy of TSS), 1976 (Box 10:299)
    - Letters to JO as poetry editor of The Village Voice (most poetry enclosures have been removed), 1976 (Box 10:300)
    - Submissions to the poetry editor of The Village Voice, 1976-1982 (Box 10:301)
    - Correspondence responding to JO's use of capital letters in his The Village Voice columns, 1977 (Box 10:302)
    - Correspondence and ephemera regarding William Saroyan tribute at which JO appeared, 1981 (Box 10:303)
    - Notre Dame University Sophomore Literary Festival, 1983-1984 (Box 10:304)
    - Correspondence, planning notes, and ephemera for "Poetry of Place" conference organized by JO at RIT in 1985; correspondenc by Bertholf, Budbill, Butterick, DiPrima, and others, 1984-1985 (Box 10:305)
    - Correspondence - not identified, ca. 1960-1962 (Box 10:306)
    - Correspondence - not identified, ca. 1962-1966 (Box 10:307)
    - Correspondence - not identified, ca. 1967-1969 (Box 10:308)
- Series II: Poetry, undated, 1953-1987
  - Subseries A: Individual Poems, undated
    - 1 November 1975 (Box 11:309)
    - 11 July 1975 (Box 11:310)
    - The 150th Anniversary of the Battle of New Orleans ( In Time), ca. 1958-1962 (Box 11:311)
    - 17-18 April, 1961 ( In Time) (Box 11:312)
    - 17 March 1963 in the Park ( On Occasion) (Box 11:313)
    - 2 / 2 / 73, 1973 (Box 11:314)
    - 2 / 2 / 76 ( Names, Dates, and Places) (includes variant TSS, 1976 (Box 11:315)
    - 2 / 14 / 77, 1977 (Box 11:316)
    - 21 March 1976 (Box 11:317)
    - 23 March ( Names, Dates, and Places), ca. 1972-1976 (Box 11:318)
    - 26 November 1970 ( On Occasion) (Box 11:319)
    - 3 / 19 / 72 (Box 11:320)
    - 3 / 20 / 72 ( Names, Dates, and Places), 1972 (Box 11:321)
    - 3 April 1972, ca. 1972 (Box 11:322)
    - 3 Poems for the Annunciation (second page torn), ca. 1960 (Box 11:323)
    - 3rd of April ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 11:324)
    - 5 November 1958 (multiple versions) (Box 11:325)
    - 6 / 24 / 73 for Pete, 1973 (Box 11:326)
    - A ( The Dutiful Son), 1953-1955 (Box 11:327)
    - The Aces ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 11:328)
    - The Acolyte ( The Dutiful Son), 1953-1955 (Box 11:329)
    - An Acrostic for Dennis, 1974 (Box 11:330)
    - The Act ( On Occasion), ca. 1970 (Box 11:331)
    - The Active Natives, ca. 1958-1966 (Box 11:332)
    - Acts ( New Spaces) (includes variant TSS and clipping), 1975 (Box 11:333)
    - Adornment of Body Poem ( Del Quien Lo Tomo), 1975 (Box 11:334)
    - African Memories ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 11:335)
    - After a Poem ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 11:336)
    - After the War is Over (includes variant TSS titled "Review"), 19774-1976 (Box 11:337)
    - Ah, These Ungenerous Lovers ( On Occasion), 1958 (Box 11:338)
    - Ahza, ca. 1962-1963 (Box 11:339)
    - The Alba ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 11:340)
    - Alba: East Third Street ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 11:341)
    - The All-Star ( On Occasion), ca. 1965-1970 (Box 11:342)
    - An Alphabet, 1961 (Box 11:343)
    - All the Spring Flowers (includes variant TSS), ca. 1962-1970 (Box 11:344)
    - Almost a Blessing, ca. 1973-1977 (Box 11:345)
    - The American School ( On Occasion) (includes variant TSS), 1960-1970 (Box 11:346)
    - America vs. Mr. Groundhog, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 11:347)
    - Amerika, the Beautiful ( On Occasion), 1970 (Box 11:348)
    - Anarchists ( Why Not), ca. 1983-1984 (Box 11:349)
    - And Jesus, 1953 (Box 11:350)
    - And if Rimbaud, ca. 1960-1970 (Box 11:351)
    - And on the Seventh Day ( On Occasion) (includes variant), 1969 (Box 11:352)
    - Anniversary ( The Love Bit), 1957 (Box 11:353)
    - An Anniversary ("Minnie and Sam Bukberg 2 July 1967") ( On Occasion) (Box 11:354)
    - The Anniversary of One Death, the Date of Another, 7/22 ( Names, Dates, and Places), ca. 1972-1978 (Box 11:355)
    - Another Country (includes variant TSS, "The Brag"), ca. 1958-1962 (Box 11:356)
    - Another Old Man Gone ( On Occasion), ca. 1966-1971 (Box 11:357)
    - The Answer ( The Dutiful Son), 1955 (Box 11:358)
    - The Answer Not Given ( New Spaces) (includes variant TSS), 1975-1983 (Box 11:359)
    - Anti-Semitism ( On Occasion), ca. 1968-1970 (Box 11:360)
    - The Anybody Blues ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 11:361)
    - Apocrypha ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 11:362)
    - Apologia Pro Sua Dylan ( On Occasion), 1970 (Box 11:363)
    - An Apology, ca. 1960-1966 (Box 11:364)
    - The Apples ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 11:365)
    - An Approach to Le Bain ( The Dutiful Son), 1955 (Box 11:366)
    - April Fool ( The Love Bit), 1957-1958 (Box 11:367)
    - The Argument (includes variant TSS, "The Lesson"), ca. 1977-1979 (Box 11:368)
    - Aromas ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 11:369)
    - Art, ca. 1980-1985 (Box 11:370)
    - As This Rain Falls ( On Occasion), 1965 (Box 11:371)
    - As We Go Marching On ( On Occasion), ca. 1971 (Box 11:372)
    - At Eleven Fifteen ( On Occasion), ca. 1965-1971 (Box 11:373)
    - 374 Autumn ( New Hampshire Journal) (includes variant TSS), ca. 1976-1980 (Box 11:374)
    - Autumn ( Del Quien Lo Tomo), ca. 1982 (Box 11:375)
    - Balling ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 11:376)
    - Balso's Blues ( On Occasion) (includes variant TSS), 1960-1970 (Box 11:377)
    - Batshebe Seen, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 11:378)
    - Beach, ca. 1958-1966 (Box 11:379)
    - Because All Asses Need Kissing, ca. 1972-1974 (Box 11:380)
    - 381 The Beer Hall Putsch ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 11:381)
    - A Beginning ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 11:382)
    - Benediction ( Collected Later Poems) (TSS not titled), ca. 1984-1988 (Box 11:383)
    - Bertha Wasserman, 1974 (Box 11:384)
    - Big Aye Poem ( On Occasion), ca. 1958-1962 (Box 11:385)
    - Billie's Blues ( Why Not), 1983-1985 (Box 11:386)
    - A Birth ("For Kristin") ( On Occasion), 1969 (Box 11:387)
    - A Birthday ("Bertha Wasserman") ( On Occasion), 1969-1971 (Box 11:388)
    - A Birthday ("Moses Sugden"), 1971-1980 (Box 11:389)
    - A Birthday ("such/ truth"), 1971-1980 (Box 11:390)
    - A Birthday ("The year is to grow on"), 1971-1980 (Box 11:391)
    - Birthday, Birthday, Burning Bright, 1975 (Box 11:392)
    - Birthday Presence, ca. 1960-1970 (Box 11:393)
    - Birthdays ( On Occasion), ca. 1966-1970 (Box 11:394)
    - The Birthright ( Names, Dates, and Places), ca. 1972-1978 (Box 11:395)
    - Blonde Ladies' Sonnet ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 11:396)
    - Blood ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 11:397)
    - Blue Funk ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 11:398)
    - The Body Politic ( On Occasion), ca. 1965-1970 (Box 11:399)
    - Book Review ( On Occasion), ca. 1966-1970 (Box 11:400)
    - The Boys Whose Fathers ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers) (includes variant MSS version), 1959-1962 (Box 11:401)
    - The Breadwinner ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 11:402)
    - Breast Poem ( The Woman Poems) (includes variant TSS), ca, 1973-1975 (Box 11:403)
    - The Bridge ( Collected Later Poems), 1985 (Box 11:404)
    - Bronxus ( In Time), ca. 1958 (Box 11:405)
    - Brother Poem ( The Woman Poems) (variant TSS), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 11:406)
    - The Brushes ( In Time) (includes severe variant TSS), 1962-1968 (Box 11:407)
    - Burning it Down, ca. 1973-1975 (Box 11:408)
    - The Bye-Bye Happiness Swing ( In Time), ca. 1962-1968 (Box 11:409)
    - Cacti ( New Spaces), 1975 (Box 11:410)
    - The Camel in Cleo's Needle, ca. 1962-1968 (Box 11:411)
    - Camille Older ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 11:412)
    - Cartography ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 11:413)
    - Celebrating the Peace ( Names, Dates, and Places), 1975 (Box 11:414)
    - A Celebration ( The Dutiful Son), 1953-1955 (Box 11:415)
    - The Champion 2 / 25 / 64 ( In Time) (includes variant TSS), 1964 (Box 11:416)
    - A Change ( On Occasion), 1960-1970 (Box 11:417)
    - Changes ( Why Not), ca. 1983-1985 (Box 11:418)
    - Chaos ( New Hampshire Journal) (copy only, not titled), ca. 1983 (Box 11:419)
    - Charivari, ca. 1960-1966 (Box 11:420)
    - The Charm ( Why Not), ca. 1983-1984 (Box 11:421)
    - The Chart ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 11:422)
    - Charts, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 11:423)
    - Child Poem ( The Woman Poems) (TSS not titled), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 11:424)
    - Cities This City ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 11:425)
    - Clams on the Half Shell ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959 (Box 11:426)
    - The Clash ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 11:427)
    - The Class, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 11:428)
    - Clothes Poem ( The Woman Poems) (variant TSS), 1973-1975 (Box 11:429)
    - Columbus Day, ca. 1966-1970 (Box 11:430)
    - Come on Baby ( On Occasion), 1960-1970 (Box 11:431)
    - Commentary ( Names, Dates and Places) (includes variant TSS, "Notes Which Will Elucidate..."), ca. 1972-1978 (Box 11:432)
    - Commercial, ca. 1983-1987 (Box 11:433)
    - The Concrete Ass, ca. 1960-1964 (Box 11:434)
    - The Cop-Out ( In Time), 1962-1963 (Box 11:435)
    - A Corny Poem ( On Occasion), 1970 (Box 11:436)
    - The Correspondents ( Why Not), ca. 1983-1984 (Box 11:437)
    - Country Alba ( New Hampshire Journal) (original MSS), 1983-1984 (Box 11:438)
    - The Couple ( The Dutiful Son), 1953-1955 (Box 11:439)
    - Credo ( New Hampshire Journal), ca. 1982-1984 (Box 11:440)
    - A Cricket Sonata, ca. 1960-1966 (Box 11:441)
    - Cultural Oppression ( Names, Dates, and Places), ca. 1972-1978 (Box 11:442)
    - The Cushion Poem, ca. 1960-1970 (Box 11:443)
    - Dab of Cornpone ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 11:444)
    - Daddy Warbucks, Punjab, Asp, ca. 1960-1970 (Box 11:445)
    - Dance as Seen ( On Occasion), 1960-1970 (Box 11:446)
    - Dancer (re-typing of poem published in 1951), 1951, 1985 (Box 11:447)
    - Dancers, ca. 1966-1970 (Box 11:448)
    - David 2 / 4/ 36, ca. 1975? (Box 11:449)
    - Dear Miss Monroe ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 11:450)
    - Death and Knowledge, ca. 1980 (Box 11:451)
    - Death Poem ( The Woman Poems) (TSS not titled), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 11:452)
    - Debt ( Collected Later Poems) (includes variant), ca. 1985-1987 (Box 11:453)
    - Definition Poem ( The Woman Poems) (TSS not titled), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 11:454)
    - Difficult Grace ( Names, Dates, and Places) (w/ variant), 1974 (Box 11:455)
    - Dirty Drawing ( On Occasion), ca. 1966-1971 (Box 11:456)
    - Dirty Picture Poem ( The Woman Poems) (TSS not titled), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 11:457)
    - Dirty Story, ca. 1961? (Box 11:458)
    - Discovery ( New Hampshire Journal), ca. 1982-1984 (Box 11:459)
    - Discovery Poem ( The Woman Poems) (TSS not titled), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 11:460)
    - Doing It ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 11:461)
    - Double Haiku, 1972-1976 (Box 11:462)
    - The Dream ( New Spaces), ca. 1979 (Box 11:463)
    - Dream Mother Poem ( The Woman Poems) (TSS not titled), ca. 1974 (Box 11:464)
    - Dream Poem ( The Woman Poems) (TSS not titled), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 11:465)
    - Dreams of Glory ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 11:466)
    - Drunk Song ( On Occasion), ca. 1965-1970 (Box 11:467)
    - Dutch Interior: Sewing ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 11:468)
    - The Economy of Art ( In Time), ca. 1962 (Box 11:469)
    - Education: The Museum of Our Youth ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 11:470)
    - Elephant Blues ( Collected Later Poems) (includes variant TSS and news clippings), 1986 (Box 11:471)
    - E. P. 1885-1972 ( Names, Dates, and Places), ca. 1972 (Box 11:472)
    - Epithalamion, 1976 (Box 11:473)
    - Ethics (includes TSS variant and MSS draft), ca. 1972-1976 (Box 11:474)
    - Ethnological Art, ca. 1972-1978 (Box 11:475)
    - "-etic" ( Why Not), ca. 1983-1984 (Box 11:476)
    - Eulogy, ca. 1960-1970 (Box 11:477)
    - Eve, ca. 1957 (Box 11:478)
    - Evening ( New Hampshire Journal) (includes variant TSS and original MSS), ca. 1982-1984 (Box 11:479)
    - Evening Star, 1953 (Box 11:480)
    - Evensong, ca. 1960-1964 (Box 11:481)
    - Even Though, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 11:482)
    - Events ( On Occasion), ca. 1966-1970 (Box 11:483)
    - Everytime Wondering ( The Woman Poems), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 11:484)
    - The Excuses ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 11:485)
    - Eyes for You ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 11:486)
    - A Fable ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 11:487)
    - The Fake Smile ( In Time) (includes MSS version and TSS draft "The Lake Isle" w/ corrections), ca. 1962-1964 (Box 11:488)
    - A Family's Passover Graces ( Collected Later Poems) (includes variant TSS, "Pesach 1983") (Box 11:489)
    - Fantasy Poem ( The Woman Poems) (variant TSS, not titled), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 11:490)
    - Farmer that Found Horses, ca. 1973-1975 (Box 11:491)
    - Father Poem ( The Woman Poems) (includes multiple TSS variants), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 11:492)
    - February ( Collected Later Poems), ca. 1984 (Box 11:493)
    - February 14, 1976 (Box 11:494)
    - Fencer, ca. 1958-1964 (Box 11:495)
    - Fighting it Out on This Line if it Takes All Summer ( In Time), ca. 1967 (Box 11:496)
    - Figure ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 11:497)
    - Fine Movement (includes variant TSS), ca. 1958-1962 (Box 11:498)
    - Finishing Poem, 1960-1962 (Box 11:499)
    - Fire in the Windowbox, ca. 1962-1964 (Box 11:500)
    - First, ca. 1956-1960 (Box 11:501)
    - First Law of Realism, ca. 1957-1962 (Box 11:502)
    - First Poem for My Last Son ( Names, Dates, and Places) (includes variant TSS), ca. 1972-1978 (Box 11:503)
    - First Song at Saint Andrews ( Names, Dates, and Places) (includes TSS with First, Second, and Third Songs), ca. 1972-1978 (Box 11:504)
    - Five Act Play ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers) (includes variant TSS, "Kind of a Five Act Play"), 1959-1962 (Box 11:505)
    - Five Songs ("for the Clancy Boys to Fiddle With") (includes "Sad Song", "Man's Song", "Spring Song", "A Wedding Song", "Short Song"), c. 1968-1970 (Box 11:506)
    - Flesh Poem ( The Woman Poems), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 11:507)
    - Flitch of Dunmow ( Why Not), ca. 1983-1984 (Box 11:508)
    - Flora ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers) (includes variant TSS, "Floral Piece"), 1959-62 (Box 11:509)
    - Flowering Avocado Tree ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 11:510)
    - Flowers ( Why Not), 1976 (Box 11:511)
    - Footprints of Man-like Creatures Found ( New Spaces) (includes news clipping of source story), 1975-1983 (Box 12:512)
    - For a Birthday, 1958 (Box 12:513)
    - For a Christening ( On Occasion), 1969 (Box 12:514)
    - For a Friend and His Wife, ca. 1958-1964 (Box 12:515)
    - For a Goddaughter ( On Occasion) (includes variant TSS), ca. 1965-1970 (Box 12:516)
    - For a Lady, After Vidal ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 12:517)
    - For a Man (" leon seidel") ( On Occasion), 1968 (Box 12:518)
    - For a Minister ( On Occasion), 1966 (Box 12:519)
    - For an Anniversary ("lewis and helene herman"), 1980 (Box 12:520)
    - For Andrew David Dillman, 1983 (Box 12:521)
    - For Anne ("2 April 1967") ( On Occasion) (Box 12:522)
    - For Anne ("3 March 1967") ( On Occasion) (Box 12:523)
    - For a Painter Beyond Hazardville ( Why Not) (includes variant TSS, "Alfred Beyond Hazardville"), ca. 1983-1985 (Box 12:524)
    - For Archie, ca. 1973-1975 (Box 12:525)
    - For Aunt Bert and Uncle Harry, 1974 (Box 12:526)
    - For a Wedding ("16 October 1965") ( On Occasion), 1968 (Box 12:527)
    - For a Wedding ("25 April 1968 Jerry & Roz") (Box 12:528)
    - For a Wedding ("Victor and Roberta"), 1976 (Box 12:529)
    - For a Wedding ("What it is we all..."), ca. 1957-1964 (Box 12:530)
    - For a Young Poet in a Dry Season, ca. 1971-1972 (Box 12:531)
    - For Basil Bunting ( Collected Later Poems), 1985 (Box 12:532)
    - For C. B. ( On Occasion) (includes MSS), 1971 (Box 12:533)
    - For Charles Reznikoff ( Names, Dates, and Places), ca. 1976 (Box 12:534)
    - For Cottie, 1975 (Box 12:535)
    - For Danielle ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 12:536)
    - For Danny, undated (Box 12:537)
    - For David ( On Occasion), ca. 1965-1970 (Box 12:538)
    - For David and Jeanie ( Collected Later Poems), 1985 (Box 12:539)
    - For Dick Quinn, 51, and John Leo, 40, 1975 (Box 12:540)
    - For DW's Wedding (includes MSS), ca. 1972-1976 (Box 12:541)
    - For Fee and Barbara (draft of personal card?), 1962 (Box 12:542)
    - For Forty ( On Occasion), 1970 (Box 12:543)
    - For George and Vickie, 1976 (Box 12:544)
    - For Han Yu After Almost 1200 Years ( New Spaces) (includes variant TSS), ca. 1975-1980 (Box 12:545)
    - For Halley's Comet ( Collected Later Poems), ca. 1986-1987 (Box 12:546)
    - For Helen 2 / 2 / 72 (with color-by-numbers groundhog), 1972 (Box 12:547)
    - For James Laughlin ( Collected Later Poems), ca. 1975-1983? (Box 12:548)
    - For Jean, Her Birthday, 1974 (Box 12:549)
    - For Jeff and Lisa ( Collected Later Poems) (includes original MSS), 1987 (Box 12:550)
    - For Joe, His Fortieth, ca. 1975-1977 (Box 12:551)
    - For John and Lucy ( On Occasion), 1970 (Box 12:552)
    - For John and Rona ( On Occasion), ca. 1972 (Box 12:553)
    - For John Dobbs, 1972 ( Collected Later Poems), ca. 1972 (Box 12:554)
    - For Karen, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 12:555)
    - For K B O, 1976 (Box 12:556)
    - For Leo Hamalian, ca. 1983-1984 (Box 12:557)
    - For Louis Zukofsky ( New Spaces), ca. 1978 (Box 12:558)
    - Formal Verse, Father of Seventy Three ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 12:559)
    - For Matthew, Dead ( On Occasion) (includes obituary), 1967 (Box 12:560)
    - For Maurice, ca. 1973-1983 (Box 12:561)
    - For Max ( Collected Later Poems), ca. 1983-1984 (Box 12:562)
    - For Michael and OK Hee, 1974 (Box 12:563)
    - For My Father ( On Occasion) (TSS has no title), ca. 1960-1970 (Box 12:564)
    - For My Father, One Year Older ( On Occasion), ca. 1963 (Box 12:565)
    - For My Grandmother ( On Occasion), 1954 (Box 12:566)
    - For My Mother, 1975 (Box 12:567)
    - For My Parents ("on their fortieth anniversary"), ca. 1961-1962 (Box 12:568)
    - For My Wife's Grandfather, Dead, 1967 (Box 12:569)
    - For Nat and Elaine, a Batch of Sangria ( On Occasion) (includes variant TSS, "A Wedding Song"), ca. 1970 (Box 12:570)
    - For Nicholas, ca. 1958-1962 (Box 12:571)
    - For Nicholas and Daniel, ca. 1962 (Box 12:572)
    - For Nick and Sharon ( Collected Later Poems), 1985 (Box 12:573)
    - For Pat and Larry, 1980 (Box 12:574)
    - For Pete Hamill, His Fiftieth ( Collected Later Poems), ca. 1982-1984 (Box 12:575)
    - For Peter 17 July 1975 (Box 12:576)
    - For Peter and Mary on Their Wedding ( On Occasion), 1968 (Box 12:577)
    - For Robert and Anne ( Collected Later Poems), 1980 (Box 12:578)
    - For Sebastian, One-Third this Month, 1972 (Box 12:579)
    - For Sylvester, ca. 1973-1980 (Box 12:580)
    - For the Annual Reading ( Names, Dates, and Places), 1975 (Box 12:581)
    - For the Barbers ( The Love Bit), 1957-1961 (Box 12:582)
    - For the Birds, ca. 1960-1966 (Box 12:583)
    - For the Bulls, ca. 1960-1966 (Box 12:584)
    - For the Eighth Street Visitors, ca. 1972-1980 (Box 12:585)
    - For the Inauguration of William R. O'Connell, Jr., 1985 (Box 12:586)
    - For the New Year, 1971 ( On Occasion) (Box 12:587)
    - For the O-Yanks ( New Spaces), 1979 (Box 12:588)
    - For Those, There ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 12:589)
    - For the Skiers, ca. 1962-1966 (Box 12:590)
    - For the Wedding of Suzanne Sylvester ( Collected Later Poems) (includes variant TSS, "7 July 1984" and Original MSS) (Box 12:591)
    - For the Younger, 1958 (Box 12:592)
    - For Tom Blackburn ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 12:593)
    - For Victor and Roberta ("4 April 1976") (Box 12:594)
    - For Vine, ca. 1975-1977 (Box 12:595)
    - For William Carlos Williams ( On Occasion), ca. 1953? (Box 12:596)
    - For Willie Sutton ( New Spaces), 1980 (Box 12:597)
    - Found Art ( In Time), 1964 (Box 12:598)
    - Found Son Poem ( The Woman Poems) (variant TSS), 1973-1975 (Box 12:599)
    - Four Fathers ( New Spaces), ca. 1975-1983 (Box 12:600)
    - Four Photographs by Richard Kirstel, ca. 1966-1971 (Box 12:601)
    - Fourth Ark Royal ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1961 (Box 12:602)